In heaven, we shall be birds flying side by side.
On earth, we shall be branches twined together.
Chen,
spending one night with you
is better than three years with Zhao Huaijin.
Liu Rumei,
you knelt before me and swore
to love me for a lifetime.
And now look at you.
You took off your clothes and rolled around with Chen Wenyuan.
What a stinking, despicable pair of dogs.
Lady Hong,
don't you hate those who break their oaths and betray their lovers the most?
Today, I swear by my blood.
Drag them to hell for me.
Chen!
Didn't you want to be together forever?
Fine.
I will grant your wish.
I want you to be together,
together for all eternity.
Make way.
Lord Su is here.
I heard the imperial court sent down
a Lord Su who has solved many strange cases.
What Lord Su?
How can a woman solve cases?
She probably used some crooked means
to get promoted.
Look at her figure and looks.
It's a pity for her to be a minor official.
The male corpse is Chen Wenyuan, the young master of Chen's Rice Shop.
The female corpse is Liu Rumei, the daughter of Liu's Silk Shop.
Both are married.
They eloped seven days ago.
Last night,
they were suddenly cursed
and died accidentally.
Whose curse?
Lady Hong,
the most famous vengeful ghost here.
Her original name was Lin Hongyuan.
She fell in love with a poor scholar
and made money to support his studies.
After the scholar passed the imperial examination,
he abandoned her.
Lady Hong was sold to a brothel.
Unable to bear the humiliation,
she threw herself into the river and committed suicide.
This is no accident,
nor is it any vengeful ghost's revenge.
Both were married.
The most likely cause is a crime of passion.
Go investigate their families.
Have the coroner examine the bodies immediately.
I want to know their time of death.
This...
How do we investigate this?
Within three days,
I want to know the case details.
If you can do it, do it.
If not, leave.
You...
Lord Su,
you're really throwing your weight around.
Young master.
Lord Su,
you shouldn't speak so absolutely.
What if you're wrong?
Who are you
to mislead the public with rumors?
Lord Su, don't go too far.
This is our magistrate's nephew.
He also came back from Chang'an.
I don't care whose nephew he is.
He can't interfere with my case.
No...
And you guys,
three days.
You...
Who is she?
A petty official from Chang'an's Dali Court.
I heard she has bad intentions.
Rumor has it she wanted a promotion,
and even seduced her direct superior.
That's why she was demoted.
Yes.
Following our office's investigation
into the recent case of Chen Wenyuan and Liu Rumei,
it has been ruled an accident,
and the case is now closed.
Sir,
this case is absolutely no accident.
I will find out the truth within two days.
Investigate my ass!
The victim died of traumatic blood loss.
The killer sewed dozens of stitches with red thread.
I can't even pick them apart.
What is that tattoo?
It's called the Xuanji Tu.
It's a love poem written by Su Hui to her husband in the Former Qin.
It's a poem that can be read forwards and backwards.
It's also the poem that Hong Niangzi
and her lover used as a token of their love.
What about the time of death?
It's still uncertain.
Find out as soon as possible.
Madam,
Lord Su from the county office is here.
Mrs. Chen,
where were you last night?
Madame was at home all night.
Do you know about Chen Wenyuan and Liu Rumei?
I just found out today.
He eloped with his little lover
and died.
And you're still in the mood to mourn him here?
Actually, Wenyuan and Liu Rumei were childhood sweethearts.
If his father hadn't forced him before he died,
he wouldn't have married me.
I can only blame my bitter fate.
Have you heard about the Red Lady?
This is my husband's mourning hall.
Don't speak nonsense.
See the guest out.
Lord Su,
my master is no longer pursuing this.
Please stop investigating.
From the county office.
I want to see your young master.
My Lord,
my young master went to Chang'an to study a few days ago.
He hasn't returned.
Someone passed away in your family,
yet you haven't set up a mourning hall.
This is our family's affair.
There is no need for you to worry, Lord Su.
Lord Su.
The Zhao family
is a prominent and wealthy family.
Sneaking in so recklessly
might be dangerous.
Are you following me?
Me, following you?
I am also a member of the county office,
and I am here to investigate the case.
A playboy like you wants to investigate a case?
Don't follow me
and become a burden to me.
Everyone says you rely on your beauty to get promoted.
You...
I...
I know you are not that kind of person.
Blow the whistle if you're in danger.
No,
you fool.
Damn it,
aren't you afraid of the Red Lady taking your life?
With the Heavenly Master's talisman,
there's nothing to fear.
Come.
I am already carrying Chen Wenyuan's child.
Then tonight I must really
teach him a lesson.
Slow down.
Zhao Huaijin,
what are you doing?
You found out about Chen Wenyuan and Liu Rumei,
and became jealous.
So,
by disguising as the Red Lady,
you killed them,
didn't you?
I was going to make a sacrifice today
to send the Red Lady back to the underworld
by using a paper figure as a substitute.
But since you delivered yourself to me,
it's your bad luck.
Zhao Huaijin,
stop playing tricks here.
Come out!
Knockout gas.